Mehreen Stavri

www.linkedin.com/in/mehreenstavri

Senior User Experience Designer / Information Architect with over 10 years' experience in UX across multiple industries, including transport, financial services, telecom and government.

My experience covers a range of responsibilities, including facilitating workshops, capturing requirements, producing user journeys, and creating high-fidelity, interactive wireframes for mobile, tablet and desktop.

I have extensive experience of working on large-scale projects within multi-disciplinary teams and value the importance of each role at all stages of a project.

Work experience

Senior User Experience Designer

Splendid Unlimited, London, UK

Feb 2014 - Feb 2018

- Creating high-fidelity, clickable wireframes in Axure for mobile, desktop and tablet.
- Leading and facilitating client workshops.
- · Capturing requirements (user and business).
- Developing user stories.
- · Creating personas.
- Producing user journeys and scenarios.
- Simplifying complex interactions and journeys.
- Producing sketches and paper prototypes to illustrate early ideas and concepts.
- · Creating page templates for site redesign.
- · Producing sitemaps.
- Designing and contributing to pattern libraries.
- Producing UX specs and documentation.
- Delivering presentations to senior clients.
- Redesigning entire sites.
- · Performing market reviews and research.
- Producing competitor landscapes and analysis.
- UX design reviews.
- Client pitches producing and delivering client pitch documents.
- Strategy developing and proposing ideas to clients.
- Proposing a service design approach built on the foundation of a services framework.

Senior User Experience Architect

Hugo & Cat, London, UK

Sep 2013 - Jan 2014

- Producing wireframes and UX specification documents.
- Competitor landscaping and research.
- Conceptualising and wireframing ideas for features and interactions.
- Working within close-knit teams of designers, developers and copywriters.

Senior User Experience Consultant / Information Architect

Detica Creative, London, UK Sep 2008 – Sep 2013

Worked on projects across a number of

Worked on projects across a number of industries, including financial services, transport, telecommunications, government, and cyber security. Responsibilities included:

- Working with complex sites and online tools.
- Facilitating user and client workshops.
- Establishing strong work relationships with senior stakeholders.
- Capturing user and business requirements for digital content and functionality.
- Business analysis of clients' online processes.
- Conducting user research and interviews to understand mindsets, behaviours, issues, barriers, and benefits of using a client's site.
- Developing personas and user stories based on user research.
- Creating detailed user journeys.
- Card sorting.
- Designing and developing detailed wireframes in Axure, Omnigraffle and Visio.
- Creating wireframes for web, mobile and tablet.
- Redesigning client sitemaps.
- Performing content and usability audits of client sites.
- Complex analysis.
- · Customer segmentation.
- User profiling of sizeable populations.
- Risk analysis.
- Performed Needs Analysis to capture user requirements, operating skills and behaviours.

Consultant

eBenchmarkers Limited, London, UK

Apr 2005 - Sep 2008

Analysed and benchmarked the online performance of major UK credit card and general insurance companies against market competitors. Responsibilities included:

- · Benchmarking and competitor analysis.
- Online and multi-channel strategies.
- Proposing opportunities for clients to improve their online performance.
- Evaluating user journeys.
- · Web analytics.
- Online conversion proposing ways to achieve best practice conversion rates.
- · Creating user data matrices.
- Historical trends, growth rates and share of market.
- Online marketing analysis compared click-through metrics and cost/efficiency of sponsored search, SEO, aggregator, affiliate and display marketing.
- Creating user and online metrics; identified ways to graphically represent these metrics.
- Customer value and methods of retention.
- Responsible for the production and delivery of workshops and reports.
- Establishing good relationships with clients and digital marketing agencies.

Risk Analyst, Energy Trading

Nuon Energy Trading & Wholesale, Amsterdam, Netherlands Jun 2002 – Jan 2005

- Daily reporting and monitoring of power and fuels trading activity.
- · Validated trader prices against broker prices and calculated profit effect.
- Created model/report to assess daily shifts in prices and measures such as standard deviations for all commodities being traded.
- Created reports for various renewable energy products.
- Developed new models and reports in order to improve analysis of positions and results.

Risk Analyst, Energy Trading

Mirant Europe BV, Amsterdam, Netherlands

Oct 2001 - May 2002

- Received President's Award for hard work and commitment.
- Produced daily risk reports for German power market: P&L, options.
- Monitored trades (forwards and options) carried out in German market.
- Dealt with electricity trade confirmations that arose between Mirant and its counterparties.

Credit Risk Analyst

Deutsche Bank, London, UK Mar 2001 – Oct 2001

- Credit Risk Management.
- Mapped exposure of FX options and trades to counterparties.
- · Researched companies to update internal credit risk management system.
- Responsible for setting up new client hierarchies.

Skills

Software & tools

Axure - Wireframes, prototypes, sitemaps, user journeys

Omnigraffle - Wireframes, sitemaps, user journeys

Keynote, InDesign, PowerPoint, Word - UX specs, presentations, documentation

Visio - Wireframes, user journeys, flow diagrams

Excel - Analysis, metrics

SAS Enterprise Guide - Complex analysis, segmentation, profiling

Languages

Dutch - Basic conversational and reading/writing level

German - Certificate of Proficiency in German - Elementary Level 1.

Education

The London School of Economics and Political Science

BSc (Hons) Economics (2.1)

1996-2000

Modules: Macro- and Microeconomics, Quantitative Methods, Econometrics and Economic Statistics, Accounting and Finance, Development Economics, Public Economics, Demographic Description and Analysis, Economic Analysis of the European Union

Wimbledon High School, London

1989-1996

A-Levels: Mathematics (Grade A), Biology (Grade A), Economics (Grade B)

GCSEs: (5 A Grades, 4 B Grades)